<u>Sergei Belokon</u>

Sydney github.com/enkron

srj.belokon@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sbelokon

<u>enkron.org</u> <u>t.me/enkron</u>

About

Summary

Devops engineer with a bachelor's degree in CS and near the seven years of experience in some technologies and programming languages. I mainly act in a devops field: from automation of routine processes using scripting languages like Python and Bash to develop and maintain reliable systems for big data processing in cloud platforms (in particular AWS). I also have a great interest in systems programming: especially the development in Rust.

Objective

Work in areas related to software engineering: kernel/user space, devops, platform engineering, SRE, embedded systems or cybersec

Hard skills

languages (familiar)

Assembly (x86_64), C, Java, Groovy, Rust

languages (proficient)

Python, Bash

tools & technologies

Vim, Git, Jenkins, Kubernetes, Helm, Docker, Terraform, HAProxy, Docker Swarm/Compose, libvirt, LXC, Kerberos, sssd, Ansible, Nginx, BIND, systemd, SSH, LVM, make, certbot, Vagrant, VirtualBox

databases

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Apache HBase

misc

AWS (CodePipeline, EC2, RDS, EBS, CF, S3, VPC, CodeCommit), JIRA, Confluence, Salesforce, jFrog Artifactory, Hadoop, Apache Tomcat, Hive, Impala, Spark, Zookeper, Apache Kafka, Prometheus, Grafana, Grafana Mimir, Buildbot, Prometheus AlertManager

Work Experience

Morse Micro (full-time)

Dec 2022 - Present (2 years, 1 month) Devops engineer Sydney NSW, Australia

Prototyped and implemented CI infrastructure using terraform as IaC solution. The infrastructure consisted of Kubernetes cluster deployed on AWS Fargate with Jenkins application as a CI system, AWS PCA for TLS encryption, cert-manager for the certificates rotation and dockerhub as a container registry.

Configured in-cluster container registry to incrementally download big images using Harbor and SOCI index.

Prototyped and implemented CI system using Jenkins, Docker Swarm, and HAProxy. Deployed monitoring solution with Prometheus, Grafana and Grafana Mimir. Configured alerting with Prometheus AlertManager and Slack. Implemented SSO authentication using SAML2.0 and GSuite as identity provider.

Deployed self-hosted runners for bitbucket pipelines

Created and refactored bunch of groovy pipelines for developer and tester teams.

Maintained production and development infrastructures.

Nov 2021 - Oct 2022 (1 year) Devops engineer St Petersburg City, Russia

Developed Ansible playbooks for upgrade and deployment Confluence instances to the stage and production environments.

Deployed and troubleshooted Bitbucket mirror farm.

Maintained configuration for the Buildbot CI tool.

Developed CLI utility using Python for automatic migration from one CRM system to another (Salesforce to JIRA) in a fairly short period of time.

And of course my daily duties included monitoring the state of the servers, administering and configuring Linux hosts (authentication, logging, cleanup, provisioning new VMs and containers, networking problems &c), administering Atlassian stack (JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket).

EPAM Systems (full-time)

Jul 2018 - Nov 2021 (3 years, 5 months) Systems engineer St Petersburg City, Russia

Started as a L2 support engineer in a big data field. Our team was responsible for keeping the distributed data processing clusters up and running (Hadoop, Hive, Impala, Spark, HBase, Zookeper, Apache Kafka). Also this position provided me an opportunity to learn Linux internals more deeply (Linux PAM, cgroups, systemd, LVM &c). As a operation team member i was also involved into communication with the customers.

After promotion to the Devops engineer role i was developing CI/CD pipelines for customers' applications which exploited big data platform using Jenkins, Ansible, Python, Gitlab and Bash.

Modeled, developed and maintained AWS CloudFormation templates for managing and provisioning infrastructure as a code.

Refactored and evolved existing Ansible playbooks for full infrastructure configuration.

Configured Kerberos security protocol for authentication of services within Hadoop cluster.

Automated standard operations and procedures to reduce manual work and time for routines (using Jenkins scripted pipelines and Python / Bash scripts)

Provided backup and disaster recovery strategies for infrastructure (with AWS capabilities: EBS snapshots, RDS multi A-Z, S3 cross-region replication &c).

Containerized custom application for big data processing using Docker.

self-employed

May 2016 - Jun 2018 (2 years, 2 months)
St Petersburg City, Russia

Studied key principles of programming (Algorithms and data structures), software testing principles, agile software development models.

Education

Peter the Great St. Petersburg Polytechnic University (SPbPU)

Languages

English professional working proficiency IELTS test report form number: **22AU009114BELS468G** Russian native